learnzillion.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy | LearnZillion

#### Policies

####  Effective May 29, 2018 

We know you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy and the privacy of students seriously. We’ve updated our privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) and terms of use so that it more accurately describes our practices. Let us know if you have any questions. 

* * *

LearnZillion, Inc. (“LearnZillion”) is committed to protecting the privacy of students, parents, and educators, while providing students and schools with a dynamic learning and teaching environment made possible by the Internet. This Privacy Policy addresses the online privacy practices of LearnZillion. LearnZillion's products and services are intended for ultimate use by parents, teachers and students, but only school districts, teachers, or parents may sign up for LearnZillion. This Privacy Policy is applicable to all LearnZillion products and services available online (the “Site”). 

If we intend to use or disclose members' personal information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you by email. 

###  Consent by School Districts, Teachers and Parents 

If you are a student of any age, you must get permission from your school, parent or teacher to use the Site. 

LearnZillion is not offered directly to students on any basis, and school districts, teachers, or parents must first sign up for primary accounts, and then invite students to use LearnZillion through student accounts. Only school districts, teachers and parents that have obtained licenses, provided consent on behalf of students for LearnZillion to collect and use student data described in this Privacy Policy and opted to allow for student account creation can create or provide enrollment codes for students to create student accounts. 

If LearnZillion learns that a student of any age has created a primary account, that account will be deleted. Further, if LearnZillion learns that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a student of any age with the appropriate consent, we will take the necessary steps to delete it. 

###  How Are Student Accounts Created? 

We will ask you to create a LearnZillion account to access certain portions of our site. When you create an account, we will ask for your consent to collect certain types of personal information. Kindly note that any consent will be entirely voluntary. However, if you do not grant the requested consent to the processing of your personal information, the use of the LearnZillion website may not be possible. 

When school districts or teachers create primary accounts and invite students to create student accounts, they are acting on behalf of parents to give LearnZillion permission to collect the information described in this Privacy Policy, and LearnZillion is acting as a service provider to the school district or teacher. 

When the primary account belongs to a school district, student accounts will be populated in coordination with that district. Students will then be provided login information in a manner specific to that district and in accordance with district policy, which may in some cases be through a district-wide “single sign-on” or by communicating an initial login and password to the student. 

When the primary account belongs to a teacher or a parent, students are added using a name, nickname or pseudonym by the teacher or parent. LearnZillion then generates enrollment codes that students can use to register student accounts. 

###  What Information Does LearnZillion Collect About Students and Teachers? 

The information that we collect from logged-in users includes information that you voluntarily provide to us when you sign up for an account and information that is automatically collected when you are logged into the LearnZillion platform. The information collected depends on whether you are a teacher, school, parent or student. 

We maintain records for each student account of assignments that have been given (and results that have been submitted) and records of any online assessments taken by the students. 

When the primary account belongs to a teacher or a parent, we collect the student name information provided by the teacher or a parent, and then collect a username and password when the student registers. Student records are linked to teacher or parent records, which may include the teacher’s or parent’s name, email address, grade levels taught, self-reported school and school district information, and geographic information about the district such as its zip code. We also collect information about teacher’s title, subject interests and teaching experience. 

When the primary account belongs to a school district, initial information about students, teachers and schools is provided from the district’s records, and may include unique identifiers that link these records to other records in the district’s database system as well as teachers’ names and titles and the name of the teacher’s school. Districts also may provide information about a student’s grade level, the student’s username, password and email address, a statewide student identifier and information about the school that the student attends. 

In every case we also log certain detailed technical information about all users’ interactions with our Site that could be linked with users (including students). This includes the IP addresses that we get when users connect to our Site, information that is sent by web browsers automatically when they connect to our Site (such as the type of web browser, the operating system used and the time zone set on the user’s computer), the timing and frequency of how users interact with different content and different areas of our Site. 

###  How We Automatically Collect Information 

We the use following methods and tools to collect and track the automatically collected information described above. 

We set cookies so that we are able to recognize when someone is connecting to our Site who is currently logged in or who has visited before. A cookie is a data file sent to a browser from a web server and stored on the user’s computer's hard drive that allows us to recognize that browser when the user returns to our Site. To learn more about browser cookies, including how to manage or delete them, look in the Tools, Help or similar section of your browser, or visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Additionally, our video player may store local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, on users’ computers. Local shared objects cannot be managed in the same way as browser cookies. For information on managing Flash cookies, visit [http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html.](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html)

We (or our email service providers) may place a tiny image, also known as a pixel tag, in the emails we send, to tell us when you have opened the email. Our team uses this information to improve emails we send to you, and best tailor them to the needs of school districts, teachers and students. 

Like most online services, when you use the Site, we automatically collect and store details of how you used our service, such as your activity on the Site, and the frequency and duration of your visits. 

By using our Site you agree to our use of these information collection technologies. 

###  Anonymized Data 

We frequently aggregate information in a way that makes it impracticable to use that data to identify a particular person; we also sometimes maintain individual data records with personal identifiers removed, and maintain in a manner in which it is impracticable to relink it to any particular individual. In this Privacy Policy, we refer to such data as “Anonymized Data” and do not consider it to be personal information. 

###  What Student Information Can Other Users See? 

When the primary account belongs to a school district, the account administrator designated by the district can access all information we collect about students that we make available through our web-based user interface. District administrators can delegate the right to view student information in accordance with district policy. Each teacher within that school district can see only information relating to students’ participation in classes taught by that teacher (unless granted additional access by the district account administrator). 

Primary account holders who register as teachers or parents can access all information available through our user interface relating to students’ interactions with assignments created by that teacher or parent. They cannot see information that we collect in connection with a student’s interactions with assignments created by another teacher or parent. 

###  What Does LearnZillion Do With Personal Information? 

We will not share personal information we collect in any way not described by this Privacy Policy. Except as noted below, we do not share any personal information with third parties for advertising, marketing or other purposes. There is no third-party advertising on LearnZillion. We do not amass student profiles except in the furtherance of school purposes. 

We do not ask or require students to provide information beyond that which is reasonably necessary to use LearnZillion. We do not share any student login information with any third party and we do not automatically collect personal information from student accounts. Information collected from students is never used or disclosed for any third-party advertising or any kind of behaviorally targeted advertising. We do collect website usage information through third-party analytics services and Anonymized Data to help us improve our experiences for students, but such information does not contain personal information. 

We use personal information and any other information collected through the website for the following reasons: 

  * to administer the website;
  * to improve the quality and types of services that we deliver;
  * to analyze site usage and the popularity and performance of our Web pages;
  * to communicate with parents, teachers and school districts by responding to your requests, comments and questions;
  * to obtain consent from parents, teachers and school districts so that a student account may be created;
  * to diagnose technical problems;
  * to send users emails regarding service, technical and other administrative matters. These communications may also include information regarding changes in services, new service offerings and important service-related notices, such as security and fraud notices. Such communications will only be delivered to parents, teachers and school districts and will never be delivered to the site’s student users;
  * to send users alerts to notify them about pertinent activity on the site, such as messages from colleagues or upcoming assignments (“Notification Alerts”). These Notification Alerts may be sent to all users of the site, including students;
  * to provide useful analyses to users and primary account owners;
  * for billing, account management and other administrative matters; or
  * as required by applicable law or regulation.

We use this information to help us to diagnose technical problems, administer the site and improve the quality and types of services that we deliver. We may also collect, track and analyze information in aggregate form that does not personally identify users. 

###  How We Share Information 

We use third-party service providers to provide a variety of services, such as assisting us with providing customer support, hosting the Site, providing us with analytics about how people use our Site, assisting us with marketing the Site to school districts and teachers, sending and tracking responses to email, providing a framework for the delivery of assessment questions and helping us identify and track bugs and errors in the Site. All of our service providers have agreed to confidentiality and data security provisions consistent with this Privacy Policy. Third parties we work with are contractually prohibited from using any personal information for any purpose other than providing the services we request from them. 

When a school district is the primary account holder, we share information with third parties at the direction of the school district, and it is the school district’s responsibility to make such requests in a manner that is consistent with their internal policies and the law. We may also share information that we collect in the following circumstances: 

  * if we believe in good faith that it is necessary to disclose the information under any applicable law or regulation (for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena);
  * if we believe in good faith that it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person;
  * to investigate and act upon violations of the law or of our terms of use;
  * with teachers and parents who are the managers of a class so they can see information about their students or children in that class, such as the student’s or child’s name, school affiliation and activity on assignments (including time of activity and any responses to questions, extending to grades for those assignments);
  * when any user logs into LearnZillion with a third party account (such as a Google, Clever or other Learning Management System account), that third party will learn that that user has visited LearnZillion, and that information will be subject to that third party’s privacy policy and practices;
  * with third party products specifically configured by schools or districts to interoperate with LearnZillion;
  * if the information is Anonymized Data;
  * with our corporate affiliates, parents and/or subsidiaries; or
  * in other circumstances that you expressly consent to.

We will not sell student or teacher information except in connection with the sale of LearnZillion’s assets or a merger of LearnZillion with another company, and then only on the condition that such information will continue to be covered by the then-applicable Privacy Policy. If there are changes to this Privacy Policy in the future, school districts, teachers and parents may agree to those changes or choose to stop using LearnZillion and we will delete their information and the information about their students. 

We may also obtain information, including personal information, from certain third parties (such as Clever). Any personal information received from these third parties will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We sometimes combine information we receive from third parties with the personal information we collect through the Site. Any such combined information will be treated as personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Please also note that our service providers may be able to combine the data we share with them with the data they collect on their own. For example, if we share information with Clever, Clever may combine such information with the data they have already collected about you through their website. We are not responsible for such combinations of data and we encourage you to learn about their privacy and security policies before you use this site or provide our service providers with your personal information. 

###  Third Party Websites 

Our site includes some links to other sites. We are not responsible for the data collection practices on those other sites. We advise you to carefully review those sites' privacy policies before submitting personal information there. 

###  Our Security Practices 

We strive to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of the personal information we collect from children and adults. We have put in place physical, electronic and administrative procedures to safeguard and to help prevent unauthorized access to and maintain the security of personally identifiable information collected through this site. 

Primary accounts and student accounts are protected by passwords. Please keep these passwords secret to prevent unauthorized access to these accounts. If you think someone has gained unauthorized access to an account, please contact us immediately. 

We take reasonable, industry-standard measures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of personal information collected on our Site. This includes the use of encryption, firewalls and other security technologies to prevent access to the data from unauthorized parties. All connections between users and our Site are secured via encryption communication technology (SSL/TLS). All passwords are salted and hashed using the practices recommended by NIST (National Institute of Standards and Technology). We use highly rated application hosting providers who agree to perform frequent diagnostics, operating system updates, and network security monitoring. Our engineering team is committed to creating and maintaining systems to protect personal information. 

Only employees who need to access user information in order to perform their job (for example, customer service) are granted access to student information. 

While we have taken all steps to protect the personal information we collect, and we work to keep our systems in line with industry standards, no system is 100% fail proof and secure. If we discover that the security of personal information has been compromised, we will notify the parent, teacher or school district that established an account with us no more than 30 days after the discovery of such compromise. We will conduct an investigation to determine the scope of the breach or restore the integrity of our system. You consent to our use of email as a means of such notification. 

###  Your Choices Related to Your Privacy 

In order to process your information, we rely on your consent or our legitimate interests to process your data. You may withdraw your consent or object to the use of our information at any time, but you may no longer be able to access LearnZillion. 

If you have an account on our website, you can edit your information in the account section of the website. If you are unable to do this on the website, you can contact us and we'll help you make changes. We may ask you to verify your identity before we provide you with access to your information. 

You have the right to opt out of emails from us by clicking unsubscribe. You may still receive transactional emails from us related to forgotten passwords, account expiration, or other necessary communication. 

###  How You Can Delete or Edit Information or an Account 

When school districts or teachers create primary accounts and invite students to create student accounts, they are acting on behalf of parents to give LearnZillion permission to collect the information described in this Privacy Policy, and LearnZillion is acting as a service provider to the school district or teacher. For these types of primary account, all requests to review, delete or edit student information must come from the school district or teacher, and parents should make use of the school’s policies with respect to reviewing, deleting or editing such information. When parents are the primary account holders, they may delete or edit student information through the LearnZillion user interface or by contacting LearnZillion. 

If a school district or school requests deletion of data under the control of the school district or school, we will promptly delete it, subject to any legal requirement to retain or transfer that data. Note that even follow such deletion requests, we may store secure backups until they are deleted in accordance with our document retention policy. We may also preserve information as part of an investigation into violations of the law or our terms of use. 

Please note that any information you share with others on the website or content other users may have copied, is not a part of your account and may not be deleted when you delete your account. If we share your data with one of our service providers, we will use our best efforts to cause such third party to delete such data when you delete your account. 

###  How We Retain and Delete Your Data 

We will retain personal information collected in connection with an account only for as long as is necessary to provide the services to the account holder, as required by applicable laws or regulations or otherwise per the terms or a contract with a school or district. 

We may maintain Anonymized Data, including usage data, for analytics purposes. 

###  Certain Rights for EEA Persons 

Individuals in certain countries, such as the European Economic Area (the “EEA”), have certain statutory rights in relation to their personal data. These rights include the right to request access to personal data, as well as to seek to update, delete or correct their personal data. You may exercise these rights by following the steps explained above, which for holders of student accounts means making such a request to the primary account holder. If you have any problems exercising your rights or if you have any additional questions about our use of your personal data, please contact us for additional information. 

###  Data Protection Officer; Data Protection Authority 

LearnZillion has a “Data Protection Officer” who is responsible for matters relating to privacy and data protection. This Data Protection Officer can be reached at [dataprotectionofficer@learnzillion.com](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@learnzillion.com). 

You may direct questions to the Data Protection Officer. You also have the right to (i) restrict LearnZillion’s use of information that constitutes your personal data, which will cause you to lose access to LearnZillion and (ii) lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. 

###  Identifying the Data Controller and Processor 

We endeavor to be fully compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), effective as of May 25th, 2018.  We may act, depending on the circumstances, as either or both a Controller and a Processor of personal data (as those terms are defined in the GDPR). We act as the Controller of information when we ask you to provide to create an account and information that we automatically collect when you use the site. We act as the Processor of user-generated content and information provided to us by school districts and teachers. 

###  Location of Data and Processing 

This website is owned and operated by LearnZillion, located at 777 6th St NW, Floor 11, Washington DC 20001. If you are located outside of the United States, please note that personal data will be processed in the cloud by our cloud service provider (currently Amazon Web Services), which offers sufficient guarantees to implement appropriate technical and organizational safeguards that meet the GDPR’s standards. We have a data processing agreement in place with our cloud service provider, ensuring compliance with the GDPR and, in the event of any unauthorized access to, or use of, personal data, the appropriate authorities will be notified.  All information is transmitted to us by our cloud service provider, will be processed in the United States, and will be handled and protected under the terms of this Privacy Policy and applicable U.S. laws, which may not be as protective as the laws in your country. By using the site, you agree to this. 

###  Notice of Changes to This Policy 

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. You can see when it was last updated by looking at the new effective date at the top of this page. 

If we make any significant changes we'll post them prominently on our website and notify you by other means as required by law. Your continued use of the website after a revision to the Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance and agreement to the current Privacy Policy. We recommend that you periodically review the Privacy Policy to make sure you understand and are up-to-date on how we're keeping your information safe. 

###  If you don't agree with any future changes to the Privacy Policy, please contact us to terminate your account. 

You may contact us at https://learnzillion.com/contact. 

###  Special Considerations by State 

Our Privacy Policy is consistent with our obligations pursuant to the following state policies and laws regarding the collection of student data: 

**California** – In accordance with California’s Student Online Personal Information Protection Act (SB-1177 SOPIPA) and the Early Learning Privacy Information Protection Act (Cal. Bus. & Prof. Code § 22586) we: 

  * do not engage in targeted advertising to students or their parents or legal guardians;
  * do not create student profiles except in the furtherance of school purposes;
  * do not sell student information unless the sale is in connection with the sale of LearnZillion’s assets or a merger of LearnZillion with another company, and only on the condition that it will remain subject to the requirements of this Privacy Policy;
  * implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices;
  * will promptly delete a student’s covered information upon the request of a school or district.

**Colorado** – In accordance with Colorado’s Student Data Transparency and Security Act (C.R.S. § 22-16-101), we: 

  * do not engage in targeted advertising to students;
  * do not create student profiles except in the furtherance of school purposes;
  * maintain a reasonably designed information security program;
  * delete or destroy data under the control of the school district or school subject to any legal requirement.

**Connecticut** – In accordance with Connecticut’s Student Data Privacy Act (H.B. 5469, Public Act No. 16-189), we: 

  * do not engage in targeted advertising to students;
  * do not sell, rent or trade student information unless the sale is in connection with the sale of LearnZillion’s assets or a merger of LearnZillion with another company, and only on the condition that it will remain subject to the requirements of this Privacy Policy;
  * do not use student data for purposes other than the furtherance of school purposes;
  * will, upon the discovery of a breach in security, notify the parent, teacher or school district that established an account with us no more than 30 days after the discovery of such compromise. We will conduct an investigation to determine the scope of the breach or restore the integrity of our system.

**Delaware** – In accordance with Delaware’s Student Data Privacy Act (14 Del. C. § 8101A), we: 

  * implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of student data, which, at a minimum, comply with the Department of Technology and Information’s Cloud and Hosting Policy and hereby incorporate the terms and conditions set forth in the Department of Technology and Information’s Cloud and Offsite Hosting Template for Non-Public Data.
  * will promptly delete a student’s data within a reasonable time frame not to exceed 45 days if a school district or school requests deletion of data under the control of the school district or school;
  * prohibit any of our third party service providers from using any student data for any purpose other than providing the contracted service and require all of our third party service providers to agree to maintain confidentiality and data security provisions consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Georgia** – In accordance with Georgia's Student Data Privacy, Accessibility, and Transparency Act (Ga. Code Ann., §§ 20-2-660 to 20-2-668; S.B. 89), we: 

  * do not engage in behaviorally targeted advertising to students.

**Maine** – In accordance with Maine's Student Information Privacy Act (Me. Rev. Stat. tit. 20 § 951-953), we: 

  * implement and maintain reasonable security procedures;
  * delete student data within 45 days upon request from a school or school administrative unit.

**New York** – In accordance with New York Education Law (§ 2-d), we: 

  * use student data only for the purposes explicitly authorized in our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy;
  * limit internal access to student data to those individuals who are determined to have legitimate educational interests by allowing only individuals with an interest in improving the Site to have access to such data;
  * use encryption technology to protect data;
  * will, upon the discovery of a breach in security, notify the parent, teacher or school district that established an account with us after the discovery of such compromise.

**Utah** – In accordance with Utah’s S.B. 163 Student Information Amendments, we: 

  * will delete any personally identifiable student data under the control of an education entity at the completion of a contract with such education entity upon such education entity’s request, unless a student or the student’s parent consents to our maintenance of the personally identifiable student data.

**Washington** – In accordance with Washington State's Student User Privacy in Education Rights Act (SUPER) (Wash. Rev. Code § 28A.604; S.B. 5149), we: 

  * will provide prominent notice before making material changes to our privacy policy;
  * will facilitate access to and correction of student data by students or their parent or guardian through the relevant educational institution or teacher who established an account with us.

###  For More Information 

Please contact us if you have any questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy.
